Maxim Averin

e-mail: amax0703@gmail.com, location: Istanbul, Turkey, phone: +79217759076 (telegram, whatsapp)

I am backend developer with 5+ years experience worked in startups, and big corps. Led small teams up to 5 persons and created 2 startups in role of founder/product manager. One of them was analytical platform for marketplaces with 15k+ MAU

EXPERIENCE

Dex.guru

Remote

Senior backend developer

Oct 2021 - Oct 2022

- ETL-pipelines: Build ETL pipelines with 10GB data per day, refactored whole financial pipeline (candles, analytics, trading terminal) it gave x1,5 overall speed
- o Data storage: refactor internal Redis storage, optimize ElastichSearch queries, made custom admin panel for Redis
- Led data source research: connect new chains, read DEX papers (uniswap v2, uniswap v3, Curve, 1inch), implement complex algorithms for adding new DEXes in platform
- $\circ~$ Wrote and optimized solidity NFT contracts with merkle Tree storage for sale
- o Technologies: Python, FastAPI, ElasticSearch, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solidity, Kibana

X5 Retail Group

Remote

Feb 2020 - Apr 2021

- Senior Python developer
 - Lead backend development of new backoffice financial CRM "Import", made architecture, technical decisions.
 - $\circ\,$ Made JWT-token authorization flow with DRF and event-based system for trading goods
 - $\circ \ \ Paritcipated \ in \ developing \ partners-microservice \ with \ Fast API, \ Mongo DB, \ Rabbitmq, \ connected \ different \ data \ sources$
 - o Technologies: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Celery, RabbitMQ, Asyncio, Docker

• Lamoda • Middle Python/Golang developer

Moscow

June 2019 - Feb 2020

- Developed several integrations with 3-rd part services, closed dech-debt, dockerized and refactored go/python legacy projects
- Made new golang microservice "Likes" from scratch (including architecture, sql queries, deploy to production and tests), send events across services with Kafka
- o Technologies: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Docker, Go, Kafka, jsonRpc, Swagger, helm, Grafana

Earlier:

- BestDoctor: launched new internal CRM for salesmen, refactored JWT-auth flow for web and mobile, made sql optimizations, integration with different APIs. Tech: Python, DRF, Celery, GraphQL, PostgreSQL. 05/2018 05/2019
- Zerion: worked as python dev with Django/Tornado stack. Develop internal services, such as async payment processor for tracking and applying transactions in ethereum, authgateway. Wrote smart contracts with unit-tests. Organized blockchain meetup and workshops 02/2017 02/2018
- Jetbrains: summer internship at Stepik.org, made microservice that enables platform material transalations api, 2017

PROJECTS

WB Radar Co-founder (CPO, CTO)

Remote

Sep 2021 - Present

- o Analytics platform for sellers at Wildberries (top-1 marketplace in Russia, revenue \$ 1.5bil+)
- Metrics: MAU 15k B2B users, overall userbase: 35k+, 220k notifications sent everyday. More than 50mln orders, sales, warehouse reports in database.
- \circ **Zero cost marketing**: 150 users comes everyday with 50% conversion leave in product, viral growth, bloggers advertised us for free, NPS 55
- o Product: made 15+ B2B custdevs, market research, built product roadmaps & prioritirezed product features
- o Managed team of 4, hired dev and support, automize support-tools with zero-coding and custom admin-panel
- **Tech**: launched high-load service from scratch with Python asyncio, Golang message distribution microservice, Celery jobs, PostgresSQL with index optimizations, metrics in Grafana, Docker and DO for deployment

EDUCATION

ITMO University

Honors and Awards

- 3+ Hackathon prizewinner (VK, mABBYYlity, Spring hack) in 2016 2019. Roles: Pitcher, Backend, Team leader
- OpenSource at Zulip, gave talk about this experience with slides on SPb Python Meetup 29
- Prizewinner of Russian Team Olympiad in Informatics, 3rd diploma competitive programming contest at highschool

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Languages: Python, Golang, Javascript, Solidity
 Frameworks: FastApi, Django, gRPC, GraphQL

• Tools: PostgreSQL, Redis, ElastichSearch, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Celery, MongoDB, Docker, Git

• Soft skills: Product managment, Custdevs, CJM, prototyping, market research

LANGUAGES

English (Advanced), German (Pre-intermediate), Russian (Native Speaker)